A Guide to the Bob Carlin Research Notes, 1754-2006 (bulk 1840-2000)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Bob Carlin Research Notes, 1754-2006 (bulk 1840-2000)
The Library of Virginia
40709
3.6 cu. ft.
Bob Carlin
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert Carlin, June 2003.
Biographical Information
Bob Carlin was born 17 March 1953 in New York, New York. Carlin, himself an accomplished banjo player performs and researches minstrel-style banjo music and songs of the mid 1800's. He has also produced and annotated many albums of southern traditional music. Through his work as Visiting Artist at several colleges, Carlin has brought these traditional music forms to a wide range of audiences.
Scope and Content
Research Notes, 1754-2006, of Bob Carlin for his book "The Birth of the Banjo: Joel Walker Sweeney and Early Minstrelsy." The collection consists of census records, correspondence, clippings, drafts, photographs, printed materials such as journal articles, research notes, and sheet music collected by Carlin while conducting research for his book. The folders labeled research notes are arranged geographically by the state in which Carlin conducted his research; these include his handwritten notes and primary source material collected from various repositories. Of note are newspaper articles from the period which Carlin used to construct a chronology of Joel Walker Sweeney's various performances throughout the United States and in Europe with circuses and minstrel shows. Also of note are materials on several well known minstrel show performers such as Polk Miller and the Harmoneons.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Bibliographies, 1999-2001. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1977-1997. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1998. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 2000. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 2003-2006. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, not dated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Draft--Chapter Fourteen: War Years with JEB Stuart, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Drafts--Sweeney Chronology, 1998-2000. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newspapers Articles--Alabama, 1837-1859. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspapers Articles--Australia, 1849-2005. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspapers Articles--England, 1842-1843. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspapers Articles--England, 1844-2000. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newspapers Articles--Georgia, 1837-1858. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newspapers Articles--Kentucky, 1840-2000. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Newspapers Articles--Illinois and Indiana, 1860-2000. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newspapers Articles--Louisiana, 1838-2000. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newspapers Articles--Maryland, 1841-1859. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newspapers Articles--Massachusetts(Boston), 1837-1998. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Newspapers Articles--Minnesota and Wisconsin, 1860-2000. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newspapers Articles--Miscellaneous, 1754-2002. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newspapers Articles--Miscellaneous, 1840-2000. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newspapers Articles--Mississippi, 1837-2000. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newspapers Articles--Missouri, 1841-2000. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Newspapers Articles--New Jersey, 1845-1999. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Newspapers Articles--New York, 1839-1841. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspapers Articles--New York, 1842-2001. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Newspapers Articles--Pennsylvania, 1842-2000. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Newspapers Articles--South Carolina(Charleston), 1836-1999. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Newspapers Articles--Tennessee, 1849-1999. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Newspapers Articles--Texas, 1859-1999. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Newspapers Articles--Virginia(Lynchburg), 1834-1997. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Newspapers Articles--Virginia(Richmond and Petersburg), 1807-1859. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Newspapers Articles--Virginia(Richmond and Petersburg), 1836-1998. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Newspapers Articles--Washington, D.C., 1841-2000. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, 1844-1897. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Printed Material, 1907-1959. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Printed Material, 1960-1969. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1976-1988. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Printed Material, 1990-1999. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Printed Material, 2000-2005. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, not dated. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, not dated. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Research--Ebay, 2001-2002. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Research--"From Doyle to Wickham to Bollman", 1831-1963. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Research--Harmoneons, 1847-2002. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Research--Polk Miller, 1892-1935. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Research Notes--Alabama, 1971-1999. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Research Notes--Circus World Museum, 1885-1998. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Research Notes--Georgia, 1998-1999. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Research Notes--Louisiana, 1837-1999. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Research Notes--Maryland, 1758-2006. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Research Notes--Massachusetts, 1840-1999. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Research Notes--Miscellaneous, 1830-2006. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Research Notes--Miscellaneous, not dated. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Research Notes--Mississippi, 1840-1999. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Research Notes--New York, 1843-2001. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Research Notes--North Carolina, 1979-2000. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Research Notes--Ohio, 1851-1998. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Research Notes--Online Material, 1999-2006. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Research Notes--South Carolina, 1999. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Research Notes--Tennessee, 1999-2000. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Research Notes--Texas, 1843-1999. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Research Notes--Virginia, 1817-1897. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Research Notes--Virginia, 1900-2000. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Research Notes--Virginia, not dated. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Research Notes--Washington, D.C., 1854-2000. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Sheet Music, 1840-1854. (Box 8, Folder 5)